In this segment, we're gonna construct
authenticated encryption systems. Since we
在这一部分，我们将要来创建认证加密系统。
already have CPA secured encryption, and
we have secure MACs, the natural question
由于我们已经有了CPA安全的加密和安全的MAC，随之而来的问题就是
is whether we can combine the two somehow,
in order to get authenticated encryption.
我们是否可以通过某种方式来将两者结合起来从而得到认证加密系统
And if, that's exactly what we're gonna do
in this segment. Authenticated encryption
事实上，这正是我们本节将要做的。认证加密
was introduced in the year 2000, in two
independent papers that I point to at the
于2000年在两篇独立的文章里被提出，本章的最后我会讲到
end of this module. But before then, many
crytpolibraries provided an API that
在这之前，许多密码学库都提供了
separately supported CPA secure
encryption, and MAC-ing. So there was one
一个分开支持CPA安全加密和MAC的API。因此存在一个
function for implementing CPA secure
encryption. For example, CBC with a random
执行CPA安全加密的函数。例如，带随机IV的CBC
IV. And another function for implementing
a MAC. And then every developer that
还有另一个执行MAC的函数。之后每一个想要执行加密的开发者
wanted to implement encryption, had to,
himself, call separately the CPA secure
都必须分别调用CPA安全加密体系和
encryption scheme and the MAC scheme. In
particular, every developer had to invent
MAC体系。特别的，每一个开发者都必须发明
his own way of combining encryption and
MAC-ing to provide some sort of
他们自己结合加密和MAC体系的方式，从而提供一种
authenticated encryption. But since the
goals of combining encryption and MAC-ing
认证加密系统。但是认证加密还没有被定义导致将CPA加密和MAC体系
wasn't well understood since authenticated
encryption hasn't yet been defined, it
结合的目标不是很明确，因而
wasn't really clear which combinations of
encryption and MAC-ing are correct and
我们很难区分哪种结合是正确的，哪种是错误的
which aren't. And so, every project as I
said had to invent its own combination.
并且像我说的每个项目都要开发它自己的结合方式
And in fact, not all combinations were
correct. And I can tell you that the most
事实上并不是所有的结合方式都是正确的。并且我可以告诉你
common mistake in software projects were
basically incorrectly combining the
软件开发的大部分普遍错误基本上就是错误地
encryption and integrity mechanisms. So
hopefully, by the end of this module, you
将加密和诚信机制结合起来。所以希望在本章的最后，大家可以
will know how to combine them correctly,
and you won't be making these mistakes
明白如何正确地结合它们，而且自己不会犯这种错误
yourself. So let's look at some
combinations of CPA secure encryption and
那么让我们来看一些CPA安全加密和MAC结合实例
MAC, that were introduced by different
projects. So here are three examples. So,
这些是出自不同的项目提出。这有三个例子。
first of all, in all three examples,
there's a separate key for encryption, and
首先，在这三个例子中，有一个单独的密钥来加密，还有
a separate key for MACing. These two
keys are independent of one another, and
一个单独的密钥来MAC。这两的密钥相互是独立的
both are generated at session setup time.
And we're gonna see how to generate these
并且都是在会话建立阶段生成的。我们将会在之后的课程学习
two keys later on in the course. So the
first example is the SSL protocol. So the
如何生成这两个密钥。那么，第一个例子呢是SSL协议。
way SSL combines encryption and MAC in the
hope of achieving authenticated encryption
以下是为了实现认证加密,SSL将加密和MAC结合起来的方式
is the following. Basically you take the
plain text, m, and then you compute a MAC
取明文m，然后计算明文m的MAC
on the plain text, m. So you use your MAC
key, kI, to compute tag for this message
因此你用你的MAC的密钥k1来计算这个明文的标签
m. And then you can concatenate the tag to
the message and then you encrypt the
然后你可以将标签和明文联系起来，然后加密
concatenation of the message and the tag
and what comes out is the actual final cipher text.
明文和标签的联接，随后就会得出最终的密文
So that's option number one. The
second option is what IPsec does. So
这是方案一。方案二就是IPsec的原理。
here, you take the message. The first
thing you do is you encrypt the message.
现在，取明文，首先要做的就是加密明文
And then, you compute a tag on the
resulting cipher text. So you notice the
然后，计算在结果密文上的标签。然后大家可以注意到
tag itself is computed on the resulting
cipher text. A third option is what the
这个明文是基于密文结果。第三个方案是
SSH protocol does. So here, the SSH takes
the message, and encrypts it using a CPA
SSH协议。那么这里，SSH取明文，用CPA安全加密体系进行加密
secure encryption scheme. And then, to it,
it concatenates a tag of the message. The
之后，将明文和标签联系起来。
difference between IPsec and SSH, is that
in IPsec, the tag is computed over the
IPsec和SSH的不同在于，在IPsec中，标签的计算在密文之上，
cipher text, whereas, in SSH, the tag is
computed over the message. And so these
然而，在SSH里，标签的计算基于明文。
are three completely different ways of
combining encryption and MAC. And the
那么这就是结合加密和MAC的三种完全不同的方式
question is, which one of these is secure?
So, I will let you think about this for a
那么问题来了，呢一种方式是安全的？我想让大家先思考一下
second, and then when we continue we'll do
the analysis together.
然后我们一起来分析
Okay. So let's start with the SSH method. So
in the SSH method you notice that the tag
让我们先从SSH方式开始。在SSH方式中大家注意到
is computed on the message and then
concatenated in the clear to the cipher text.
标签的计算基于明文，然后将标签附在密文后面。
Now this is actually quite a problem
because MACs themselves are not designed
事实上这存在这很大的问题，因为MAC并不是
to provide confidentiality. MACs are only
designed for integrity. And in fact, there's
为了提供保密性而设计的。它只是为了完整性而设计的。并且事实上
nothing wrong with a MAC that as part of
the tag outputs a few bits of the plain
MAC作为标签的一部分输出明文中的几位是没有任何问题的
text. Outputs a few bits of the message M.
That would be a perfectly fine tag. And yet if
输出明文m中的几位。可以说这是一个很好的标签
we did that, that would completely break
CPA security here, because some bits of
但是如果我们这么做了，将会完全破坏CPA的安全性，因为明文中的
the message are leaked in the cipher text.
And so the SSH approach, even though the
的某几位会在密文中泄露。因此即使SSH的
specifics of SSH are fine and the
protocol itself is not compromised by
特性很好并且协议本身没有因这种特定
this specific combination, generally it's
advisable not to use this approach. Simply
的结合而妥协，还是不建议使用这种SSH方式
because the output of the MAC signing algorithm might leak bits of the message. So
因为MAC这种签名算法可能会泄露明文中的几位。
now let's look at SSL and IPsec. As it
turns out, the recommended method actually
因此让我们看一下SSL和IPsec方式。事实证明，被推荐的方式
is the IPsec method. Because it turns out
no matter what CPA secure system and MAC
事实上是IPsec方式。因为结果表明，无论你使用CPA安全系统还是MAC密钥
key you use the combination is always
gonna provide authenticated encryption.
结合的结果总是能提供一个认证加密
Now let me very, very briefly explain why.
Basically what happens is once we encrypt
现在让我非常简明扼要的解释一下原因。基本上，一旦我们加密明文
the message well the message contents now
is hidden inside the cipher text and now
那么明文的内容就藏在了密文中
when we compute a tag of the cipher text
basically we're locking, this tag locks
现在当我们计算密文中的标签时这个标签给密文上了锁
the cipher text and makes sure no one can
produce a different cipher text that would
并且保证没有人能够再去产生一个看起来正当的与之不同的密文
look valid. And as a result this approach
ensures that any modifications to the
因此，这个方法确保任何对密文的修改
cipher text will be detected by the
decrypter simply because the MAC isn't
将会被解密者轻易地发现，因为MAC
gonna verify. As it turns out, for the SSL
approach, there actually are kind of
无法验证。结果表明，对于SSL方式来说，事实上存在
pathological examples, where you combine
CPA secure encryption system with a secure
病态的事例，当你将CPA安全加密系统和安全MAC结合时
MAC. And the result is vulnerable to a
chosen cipher text attack, so that it does
结果对于选择密文攻击是脆弱的，因此
not actually provide authenticated
encryption. And basically, the reason that
它事实上并没有提供认证加密。基本上，这个可能发生的原因是
could happen, is that there's some sort of
a bad interaction between the encryption
在加密体系和MAC算法之间存在某种
scheme and the MAC algorithm. Such that,
in fact, there will be a chosen cipher
不好的联系。事实上，会有一个选择密文攻击
text attack. So if you're designing a new
project the recommendation now is to
如果你设计了一个新的项目，现在总是推荐先加密
always use encrypt then MAC because that
is secure no matter which CPA secure
然后计算MAC，因为无论你组合了什么样的CPA安全加密和MAC算法
encryption and secure MAC algorithm you're
combining. Now, just to set the
得到的总和总是安全的。现在看个术语
terminology, the SSL method is sometimes
called MAC-then-encrypt. And the
这个SSL方法有时叫做“先MAC后加密”
IPsec method is called encrypt-then-MAC.
The SSH method even though you're
IPsec方法叫做“先加密后MAC”。尽管我们不应该使用SSH方法
not supposed to use it, is called encrypt-and-MAC. Okay, so I'll often refer to
但它也被叫做“先加密后MAC”。所以我会经常提到
encrypt-then-MAC, and MAC-then-encrypt to
differentiate SSL and IPsec. Okay, so
“先加密后MAC”和“先MAC后加密”来区分SSL和IPsec
just to repeat what I've just said. The IPsec
method encrypt-then-MAC always
重复一下我刚才所讲，IPsec方法“先加密后MAC”
provides authenticated encryption. If you start
from a CPA secure cipher and a secure MAC
总是提供认证加密。如果你从一个CPA安全密码和一个安全MAC出发
you will always get authenticated
encryption. As I said, MAC-then-encrypt in
你将总是得到认证加密。就像我所说的，事实上
fact, there are pathological cases where
the result is vulnerable to CCA attacks and
先MAC后加密有一些病态的情况，结果对CCA攻击是脆弱的
therefore does not provide authenticated
encryption. However, the story's a little
因此它并不提供认证加密。然而，实际上
bit more interesting than that, in that,
it turns out, if you're actually using
比这要有趣。如果你使用随机计数器模式
randomized counter mode or randomized CBC,
then it turns out, for those particular
或随机CBC，那么对那些CPA安全的加密机制
CPA secure encryption schemes, MAC-then-encrypt
actually does provide authenticated
先MAC后加密确实提供了认证加密
encryption and therefore it is secure. In
fact, there's even a more interesting
因此是安全的。事实上，更有趣的是
twist here in that if you're using
randomized counter mode. Then, it's enough
如果你使用了随机计数器模式
that your MAC algorithm just be one time
secure. It doesn't have to be a fully
那么你的MAC算法只要是一次性安全的就够了，不需要是完全安全的MAC
secure MAC. It just has to be secure when
a key is used to encrypt a single message,
只需要当密钥只用于加密单个信息时是安全的即可
okay? And when we talked about message
integrity, we saw that there are actually
我们讨论信息完整性时，看到过有一些
much faster MACs that are one time secure
than MACs that are fully secure. As a
快得多的MAC算法，它们是一次性安全的，而非完全安全的MAC
result, if you're using randomized counter
mode MAC-then-encrypt could actually
因此如果你使用随机计数器模式，先MAC后加密
result in a more efficient encryption
mechanism. However, I'm going to repeat
实际上可以构造一个更有效率的加密机制。但我还要重复一遍
this again. The recommendation is to use
encrypt-then-MAC and we're going to see a
推荐使用先加密后MAC
number of attacks on systems that didn't
use encrypt-then-MAC. And so just to make
我们将看到许多针对未使用先加密后MAC的系统的攻击
sure things are secure without you having
to think too hard about this. Again, I am
为了确保安全，同时不必思考太多
going to recommend that you always use
encrypt-then-MAC. Now, once the concept of
我推荐大家始终使用先加密后MAC
authenticated encryption became more
popular, a number of standardized
现在一旦认证加密的观念变得更流行
approaches for combining encryption and
MAC turned up. And those were even
很多组合加密和MAC的标准方法便涌现出来
standardized by the National Institute of
Standards. So I'm just gonna mention three
还有些是国家标准局（NIST）的标准方法。我们将讨论其中三个标准
of these standards. Two of these were
standardized by NIST. And these are
其中两个是由NIST标准化的
called Galois counter mode and CBC counter
mode. And so let me explain what they do.
分别叫做Galois计数器模式（GCM）和CBC计数器模式（CCM）我来解释一下它们的工作过程
Galois counter mode basically uses counter
mode encryption, so a randomized counter
Galois计数器模式使用了计数器模式加密
mode with a Carter-Wegman MAC, so a very
fact Carter-Wegman MAC. And the way the
即使用Carter-Wegman MAC的随机计数器模式，一个非常快速的Carter-Wegman MAC
Carter-Wegman MAC works in GCM is it's
basically a hash function of the message
GCM的Carter-Wegman MAC如下工作：它是待求MAC的信息的一个哈希函数
that's being MACed. And then the result is
encrypted using a PRF. Now this hash
然后用一个PRF加密哈希的结果
function in GCM is already quite fast to
the point where the bulk of the running
现在GCM里的这个哈希函数已经很快了
time of GCM is dominated by the counter
mode encryption and it's even made more so
GCM的运行时间受制于计数器模式
in that Intel introduces a special
instruction PCLMULQDQ specifically
为了更快，Intel引入了一个特殊指令PCLMULQDQ
designed for the purpose of making the
hash function in GCM run as fast as possible.
特别为此设计，目标是让GCM的这个哈希函数跑的尽可能的快
Now CCM counter mode is another
NIST standard. It uses a CBC MAC and
现在CCM计数器模式是另一个NIST标准，它使用CBC MAC
then counter mode encryption. So this
mechanism, you know, this uses MAC, then
然后用计数器模式加密。这个机制使用MAC
encrypt, like SSL does. So this is
actually not the recommended way of doing
然后加密，就像SSL那样。这并不是推荐的方法
things, but because counter mode
encryption is used. This is actually a
但因为使用的是计数器模式，这实际上
perfectly fine encryption mechanism. One
thing that I'd like to point out about
是一个很好的加密机制。关于CCM我要指出一点
CCM, is that everything is based on AES.
You notice, it's using AES for the CBC
一切都是基于AES的。大家注意，它的CBC-MAC使用了AES
MAC, and it's using AES for the counter
mode encryption. And as a result, CCM can
它的计数器模式也是使用的AES
be implemented with relatively little
code. Cause all you need is an AES engine
因此CCM可以用相对少的代码实现，因为需要的仅为AES引擎
and nothing else. And because of this, CCM
actually was adopted by the Wi-Fi
其他都不需要，因为这点，CCM被Wi-Fi所采用
alliance, and in fact, you're probably
using CCM on a daily basis if you're using
事实上，你很有可能每天都在使用CCM
encrypted Wi-Fi 802.11i then you're
basically using CCM to encrypt traffic
如果你使用加密的Wi-Fi 802.11i，那么你就在使用CCM来加密
between your laptop and the access point.
There's another mode called a EAX that
你的笔记本和接入点之间的通信。还有一个模式叫做EAX
uses counter mode encryption, and then
CMAC. So, again you notice encrypt-then-MAC
使用的计数器模式加密，然后是CMAC，大家注意，这次是先加密后MAC
and that's another fine mode to
use. We'll do a comparison of all these
这是另一个很好的模式。我们待会来对这些模式做个比较
modes in just a minute. Now I wanted to
mention that first of all, all these modes are
现在我想提一下，首先，所有的这些模式都是基于新鲜值的
nonce-based. In other words, they don't
use any randomness but they do take as
换句话说它们不使用任何随机性，但它们取新鲜值为输入
input a nonce and the nonce has to be
unique per key. In other words, as you
而且每个密钥的新鲜值是唯一的，换句话说
remember, the pair (key, nonce)
should never ever, ever repeat. But the
大家记得，有序对（密钥，新鲜值）永远不该重复使用
nonce itself need not be random, so
it's perfectly fine to use a counter, for
但新鲜值本身不一定是随机的，所以完全可以使用一个计数器
example, as a nonce. And the other
important point is that, in fact, all
比如新鲜值。另一个重要的地方是，事实上
these modes are what's called
authenticated encryption with associated
所有的这些模式被称为带相关数据的认证加密（AEAD）
data. This is an extension of
authenticated encryption, that comes
这是一个认证加密的扩展
up very often in networking protocols. So
the idea between AEAD is that, in fact,
这在网络协议中经常出现，AEAD的想法是
the message that's provided to the encryption
mode is not intended to be fully
提供给加密模式的信息不被完全
encrypted.Only part of the message is
intended to be encrypted, but all of the
加密 只有部分信息是被加密的
message is intended to be authenticated. A
good example of this is a network packet.
但所有信息是被认证的 这里有一个好例子是网络数据包只有部分信息是被加密的
Think of like a IP packet where there's a
header and then there's a payload. And
考虑一个IP包 有报文头 然后是封装数据
typically the header is not gonna be
encrypted. For example, the header might
一般来说 报文头不会被加密 例如报文头可能包含
contain the destination of the packet, but
then the header had better not be
数据包的目标地址 那么报文头最好不要被加密
encrypted otherwise routers along the way
wouldn't know where to route the packet.
免得图中的路由器不知道如何路由
And so, typically the header is sent in
the clear, but the payload, of course, is
一般来说 报文头以明文形式发送 但当然
always encrypted, but what you'd like to
do is have the header be authenticated.
封装数据总是被加密的 不过你还是希望报文头被认证
Not encrypted but authenticated. So this is
exactly what these AEAD modes do. They
不用加密 但需认证 那么这就是这些AED模式的工作
will authenticate the header and then
encrypt the payload. But the header and
他们会认证报文头 然后加密封装数据
the payload are bound together in the
authentication so they can't
但在认证中 报文头和封装数据是被绑定在一起的
actually be separated. So this is not
difficult to do. What happens is in these
这样它们不能分开 这不能做到
three modes GCM, CCM, and EAX, basically
the MAC is applied to the entire data. But
在这三种模式GCM CCM和EAX中 MAC应用到整个报头文数据上
the encryption is only applied to the part
of the data that needs to be encrypted.
不过加密只被应用到部分需要加密的数据上
So I wanted to show you what an API
to these authenticated encryption with
所以我想为大家展示一个带相关数据的认证加密的API
associated data encryption schemes look
like. So here's what it looks like in OpenSSL.
长什么样 它在OpenSSL中长这样
For example, this is, an API
for GCM. So what you do is you call the
例如 这是一个GCM的API 你可以调用init函数
init function to initialize the encryption
mode, and you notice you give it a key and
来初始化这个加密模式 然后注意到它一个密钥和新鲜值
the nonce. The nonce again,
doesn't have to be random, but it has to
这个新鲜值也不必是随机的 但它必须是唯一的
be unique. And after initialization, you
would call this encrypt function, where
初始化后 调用这个加密函数
you see that you give it the associated
data that's gonna be authenticated, but
给它需要认证 但不需要加密的相关数据
not encrypted. You give it the data, and
it's gonna be both authenticated and
然后给它需要认证和加密的数据
encrypted. And it gives you back the full
cipher text, which is an encryption of the
函数就会返回整个数据加密后的密文
data, but of course does not include the
AEAD, because the AEAD is gonna be sent in
不过当然 不包括AED 因为AED需要以明文形式发送
the clear. So now that we understand
this mode of encrypt-then-MAC, we can go
那么我们现在理解了这个“先加密后MAC”的机制
back to the definition of MAC security and
I can explain to you something that might
我们可以回到MAC的安全性定义 我可以为大家解释
have been a little obscure when we looked
at that definition. So if you remember,
定义里一些看起来略难懂的地方 如果大家还记得
one of the requirements that followed from
our definition of secure MACs meant that
安全MAC定义的要求之一是 如果大家还记得
given a message-MAC pair on a message M,
the attacker cannot produce another tag on
给定信息M的信息 MAC对 攻击者不能产生
the same message M. In other words, even
though the attacker already has a tag for
同样的信息M的另一个标签 换句话说 即使攻击者已经有了信息M的一个标签
the message M, he shouldn't be able to
produce a new tag for the same message M.
他也不能产生同样信息M的一个新标签
And it's really not clear, why does that
matter? Who cares, if the adversary already
还不太清楚为什么这点很要紧 谁在乎这点呢 如果攻击者已经
has a tag on the message M, who cares if
he can produce another tag? Well, it turns
有了信息M的一个标签 谁在乎他是否能产生另一个标签？
out if the MAC didn't have this property.
In other words, given a message-MAC pair
实际上如果MAC没有这一性质 换句话说 给定一对信息和MAC
you can produce another MAC on
the same message, then that MAC would
你能产生同样信息的另一个MAC 那么这个MAC会造成一个不安全的“先加密后MAC”
result in an insecure encrypt-then-MAC mode.
And so if we want our encrypt-then-MAC to
的模式 如果我们想让我们的“先加密后MAC”
have cipher text integrity, it's crucial
that our MAC security would imply this strong
具有密文完整性 很重要的一点是 我们的MAC的安全性
notion of security, which, of course, it
does because we defined it correctly.
蕴含着这个安全观点 当然这是因为我们定义的正确
So let's see what would go wrong, if, in
fact, it was easy to produce this type of
那么我们看会出错的 事实上容易产生这种伪造
forgery. So what I'll do is I'll show you
a chosen cipher text attack on the
我会告诉大家一种在“先加密后MAC”系统上的选择密文攻击
resulting encrypt-then-MAC system. And
since the system has a chosen cipher text
由于这个系统有一种选择密文攻击
attack on it, it necessarily means that it
doesn't provide authenticated
这就意味着它不提供认证加密
encryption. So let's see. So the
adversary's gonnna start by sending two
我们来看看 一开始 攻击者发送两个信息
messages, M0 and M1. And he's gonna
receive, as usual, the encryption of one
M0和M1 通常他会收到
of them, either the encryption of M0 or
the encryption of M1. And since we're
M0或M1的加密结果 由于我们使用“先加密后MAC”
using encrypt-then-MAC, the adversary
receives the cipher text we'll call it C0
攻击者收到的密文我们记为C0
and a MAC on the cipher text C0.
Well now we said that given the MAC on
C0上有一MAC 我们说过 给定信息的MAC
a message the adversary can produce
another MAC on the same message. So what
攻击者可以产生同样信息的另一个MAC
he's gonna do is he's gonna produce
another MAC on the message C0. Now he has
这样他将产生信息C0的另一个MAC
a new cipher text (C0,T'), which is a
perfectly valid cipher text. T' is a
现在他有了一个新的密文（C0，T') 是一个完全有效的密文
valid MAC of C0. Therefore, the adversary
now can submit a chosen cipher text query
T'是C0的一个有效MAC 所以 攻击者可以提交
on C' and this is a valid chosen
cipher text query because it's different
C'和一个选择密文的询问 这是一个有效的选择密文的询问
from C. It's a new cipher text. The poor
challenger now is forced to decrypt this
因为它和C不同 它是一个新的密文 可怜的挑战者
cipher text C' so he's going to send
back the decryption of C'. It's a
被迫去解密这个密文C' 然后发送C'的解密
valid cipher text therefore the decryption
of C prime is the message Mb but now the
它是一个有效的密文 所以C'的解密是信息Mb
attacker just learned the value of B
because he can test whether Mb is equal to
但现在攻击者就学得了b的值 因为他可以测试
M0 or MB is equal to M1. As a result he
can just output B and he gets advantage
Mb等于M0还是M1 因此他能输出b
one in defeating the scheme. And so
again if our MAC security did not imply
以优势1赢得这个机制 如果我们的MAC的安全性不蕴含这里的性质
this property here. Then, there would be a
chosen cipher text attack on encrypt-then-MAC.
那么在这个“先加密后MAC”的系统上有一个选择密文攻击
And therefore, it would not be secure. So the
fact that we define MAC security correctly
因此 它将是不安全的 所以我们正确定义了MAC的安全性
means that encrypt-then-MAC really does
provide authenticated encryption. And
意味着“先加密后MAC”的确提供了认证加密
throughout all the MACs that we discussed
actually do satisfy this strong notion of
我们讨论过的所有MAC都满足这一很强的不可伪造的观点
unforgeability. So, interestingly, this is
not the end of the story. So, as we said
有趣的是 故事还没有结束
before the concept of authenticated
encryption was introduced everyone was
我们在引入认证加密的概念之前曾经说过
just combining MACs and encryption in
various ways in the hope of achieving
人们以不同的方式组合MAC和加密 以获得认证加密
some authenticated encryption. After
the notion of authenticated encryption
在认证加密的观点被严格地形式化后
became formalized and rigorous, people
kind of started scratching their heads and said,
人们开始搔脑袋 说
hey, wait a minute. Maybe we can achieve
authenticated encryption more efficiently
嘿 等一下 或许我们可以获取到
than by combining a MAC and an encryption
scheme. In fact, if you think about how
更加有效的获得认证加密。事实上
this combination of MAC and encryption
works, let's say we combine counter mode
如果考虑MAC和加密的组合是如何工作的，比如说组合计数器模式和CMAC
with CMAC, then for every block of
plaintext, you first of all have to use
那么对每个明文分组，首先必须使用
your block cipher for counter mode, and
then you have to use to your block cipher
你的分组密码以计数器模式，然后必须再次使用分组密码
again, for the CBC-MAC. This means that if
you're combining CPA secure encryption with a
运行CBC-MAC。这意味着如果你把CPA安全的加密
MAC, for every block of plaintext, you
have to evaluate your block cipher twice,
和一个MAC组合起来，对每个明文分组，你必须计算你的分组密码两次
once for the MAC and once for the
encryption scheme. So the natural question
一次计算MAC，一次计算加密机制
was, can we construct an authenticated
encryption scheme directly from a PRP,
自然问题就来了，我们能否由一个PRP直接构建一个认证加密机制
such that we would have to only evaluate
the PRP once per block? And it turns out
这样一来我们可以对每个分组，只计算PRP一次
the answer is yes, and there's this
beautiful construction called OCB, that
实际上答案是肯定的，有这个漂亮的构造叫做OCB
pretty much does everything you want, and
is much faster than constructions that are
它能做你想要的一切，而且比从加密和MAC分别构造的机
separately built from an encryption and a
MAC. So I wrote down, kind of a schematic
快很多。那么我写下了OCB的机制
of OCB. I don't want to explain it in
detail. I'll just kind of explain it at a
我不想解释太多细节。我从高层次来解释一下
high level. So here we have our input
plain text, here at the top. And you
这里有我们的输入明文，在这上面
notice that, first of all, OCB is
parallelizable, completely parallelizable.
大家注意，首先，OCB是可并行的，完全可并行的
So every block can be encrypted separately of
every other block. The other thing to
所以每个分组可以被单独加密
notice is that as I promised, you only
evaluate your block cipher once per plain
另一件事是，如我所保证的，对每个明文分组，你只需计算一次分组密码
text block. And then you evaluate it one
more time at the end to build your
然后在最后再计算一次分组密码，以构建
authentication tag and then the overhead
of OCB beyond just a block cipher is
认证标签，那么除去分组密码部分，OCB的开销是最小的
minimal. All you have to do is evaluate a
certain very simple function P. The
你只需计算一个非常简单的函数P
nonce goes into the P you notice, the
key goes into this P and then there is a
新鲜值交给了P，密钥也给了P
block counter that goes into this P. So
you just evaluate this function P, twice
然后还有一个分组计数器交给了P。所以你只需计算这个函数P
for every block and you XOR the result
before and after encryption using the
每个分组两次，然后与之前的结果异或
block cipher and that's it. That's all you
have to do and then you get a very fast
使用分组密码加密之后，就结束了。你获得了
and efficient authenticated encryption
scheme built from a block cipher. So OCB
一个快速有效的，由分组密码构建的认证加密机制
actually has a nice security theorem
associated with it and I am going to point
所以OCB有一个附带的很好的安全性定理
to a paper on OCB when we get to end of
this module where I list some further
在本章末，我要指出一篇关于OCB的论文
reading papers that you can take a look
at. So you might be wondering if OCB is so
届时我会列出一些大家可进一步阅读的论文。大家可能想知道
much better than everything you've seen so
far, all these three standards CCM, GCM and
如果OCB比目前看到过的其他机制都好，包括CCM,GCM
EAX why isn't OCB being used or why isn't
OCB the standard? And the answer is a
以及EAX，为什么OCB没怎么被使用？为什么OCB不是标准？
little sad. The primary answer that
OCB is not being used is actually because
这是个令人悲伤的答案。OCB没被应用的主要原因
of various patents. And I'll just leave it
at that. So to conclude this section I
是因为各种各样的专利。我这里就不提了。
wanted to show you some performance
numbers. So here on the right I listed
总结一下本书，我想给大家一些性能参数
performance numbers for modes that you
shouldn't be using. So this is for
右边我列了这些大家不该用的模式的性能参数
randomized counter mode, and this is for
randomized CBC. And you can see also the
这是随机计数器模式，这是随机CBC
performance of CBC MAC is basically the
same as the performance of CBC encryption.
大家还可以看到CBC-MAC的性能和CBC加密的性能基本一样
Okay. Now here are the authenticated
encryption modes, so these are the ones
现在这里是认证加密模式
that you're supposed to using, these
you're not supposed to be using on their
所以这些是大家应当使用的模式了，右边的大家不要用
own, right. These two, you should never
ever use these two because they only
这两个，大家永远不应该使用这两个
provide CPA security, they don't
actually provide security against active
因为它们只提供CPA安全它们不提供对抗主动攻击的安全性
attacks. You're only supposed to use
authenticated encryption for encryption.
大家只应该使用认证加密来进行加密
And so I listed performance numbers
for the three standards. And let me remind
所以我列了这三个标准的性能参数
you that GCM basically uses a very fast
hash. And then it uses counter mode for
让我提醒大家，GCM使用了非常快速的哈希函数。然后它在加密中使用了计数器模式
actual encryption. And you can see that
the overhead of GCM over counter mode is
你可以看到，计数器模式的GCM的开销
relatively small. CCM and EAX both use a
block cipher based encryption and a
相对是很小的。CCM和EAX都使用了一个基于分组密码的加密
block cipher based MAC. And as a result
they're about twice as slow as counter
和一个基于分组密码的MAC。因此它们的运行时间大约是计数器模式的两倍
modes. You see that OCB is actually the
fastest of these, primarily because it
大家看到，OCB是这些当中最快的
only use the block cipher once per message
block. So based on these performance
主要是因为它对每个明文只使用一次分组密码
numbers, you would think that GCM is
exactly the right mode to always use. But
根据这些性能参数，大家会认为GCM正是应该一直使用的正确模式
it turns out if you're on the space
constrained hardware, GCM is not ideal.
但实际上，如果你在空间有限的硬件设备上，GCM并不理想
Primarily because its implementation
requires larger code than the other two
主要是因为它的实现需要比其他两个模式更多的代码
modes. However, as I said, Intel
specifically added instructions to speed
但是，如我所说，Intel特地加了指令
up GCM mode. And as a result, implementing
GCM on an Intel architecture takes
来加速GCM模式。因此在Intel体系结构上实现GCM
very little code. But on other hardware
platforms, say in smart cards or other
只需要很少的代码。但在其他硬件平台上，比如说智能卡或其他受限的硬件环境
constrained environments, the code size
for implementing GCM would be considerably
实现GCM的代码大小会比其他两个模式
larger than for the other two modes. But
if code size is not a constraint then GCM
大得多。但如果代码大小不受限制的话
is the right mode to use. So to summarize
this segment I want to say it one more
那么GCM是正确的选择。总结一下本节，我想再说一次
time that when you want to encrypt
messages you have to use an authenticated
当你想加密信息时，你必须使用认证加密模式
encryption mode and the recommended way to
do it is to use one of the standards,
推荐的方法是使用这些标准中的一个
namely one of these three modes for
providing authenticated encryption.
这三个标准中的一个，以提供认证加密
Don't implement the encryption scheme yourself.
In other words don't implement
不要自己实现加密机制。换句话说
encrypt-then-MAC yourself. Just use one of these
three standards. Many crypto libraries
不要自己先加密后MAC，就使用三个标准中的一个
now provide standard API's for these three
modes and these are the one's you should
现在许多密码学库提供了这三种模式的标准API
be using and nothing else. In the next
segment we're going to see what else can
你应该使用这些，而不是别的。下一节，我们要看
go wrong when you try to implement
authenticated encryption by yourself.
当你试图自己实现认证加密时，还会发生什么错误